



MISSION

Being a problem solver, and an artist at heart, I want to bring *my* creativity to solve tomorrow's problems, with elegant solutions.



CONTACT



+1(912) 755-7989



dehinton@usc.edu



Los Angeles, California



www.deveretthinton.com



SKILLS

C++ Python
PHP C#
HTML CSS
Javascript Web Design
VR gLUA
Mathematics Robotics
SAGE Game Design

Game Engines
Time Management
Project Direction
Digital Media Design
Community Leadership



LANGUAGE



EnglishMother Language



JapaneseLimited proficiency

D. Everett Hinton

Software Engineer — 10 years of experience



EXPERIENCE

Divinity Servers

2014-2018

A small-server hosting startup founded by me and my partner.

- Automation of configurable Linux virtual machines.
- Command line experience with remote servers.
- Front-end and back-end development of customer experience.

Undergraduate Research

2017-2018

Mathematics research on Elliptical Curves over Finite Fields at AASU.

- Constructed primality test programs in SAGE & Python.
- Attended group conferences and presented research to peers.
- Worked with a team to examine properties of Hilbert polynomials.

Freelance Programming

2013-Present

Managing a clientele base of for-comission programming tasks.

- Technical skill to create an end-product for clients.
- Team-based feedback to produce desired result.
- Knowledge of game engines and their functions.



EDUCATION

University of Southern California

2018-Present

Physics & Computer Science undergraduate student at USC.

- First generation college student.
- Research on computational solutions to the 3-body problem.
- Network operator for the school of engineering.



RECOGNITION & AWARDS

Winner of Hack for Savannah

2017

A group hackathon for improving post-hurricane city resiliance.

1st Place Winner of TechFest 2018

2018

An ACM competition for both graduate and undergraduate students.



STATEMENT

Since I was a child I have had a fascination with video games; how they worked, why they existed, and how I could make one? This kick started my entrance into the world of programming. However, after coding for *ten years*, I've realized my goal is a bit more ambitious; space. Being a firm believer that humans will shortly enter space, and knowing the crop of new problems that will arise, my dream is create a OoL solutions firm that will be two steps ahead of all these issues. The future is my passion.